MATTHEW MISKOV

Somerset, NJ ♦ 609-495-5687 ♦ mattm479@gmail.com ♦ <u>LinkedIn</u> ♦ <u>GitHub</u> ♦ <u>Portfolio</u>

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Studious Senior Software Engineer bringing 9 years of experience in the financial services industry. Indepth understanding of web technologies with focus on delivering innovative business solutions. Solid background of overseeing systems architecture, defining goals, and managing project progress with both local and remote teams. Organized and systematic team player with development experience in Agile environments and Scrum methodology.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- .NET Core 3.1 / .NET 6
- PHP
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Docker

- AWS S3, SNS, SQS, RDS
- Terraform
- Git / GitLab / GitHub
- SVN
- Jenkins

WORK HISTORY

BILLTRUST – Lawrenceville, NJ

2005 - 2023

Leading provider of cloud-based software and integrated payment processing solutions.

Senior Software Developer, 2019 – 2023

Responsible for designing, testing, and implementing new microservices as well as supporting existing ones. Followed the software development lifecycle to ensure projects were completed on time and met company specifications.

- Designed and developed a REST API and RDS MySQL database for a new reporting system that gave customers a greater insight into accounts, billing documents, and payments. The REST API used .NET Core 3.1, which was later upgraded to .NET 6, RDS MySQL, and S3.
- Designed and developed a Service Worker and RDS MySQL database for a new reporting system
 that notified consumers when it was time to load data into the data warehouse. This gave the
 consumers the flexibility to determine the optimal time to load data based on the customer's
 needs. The Service Worker used .NET Core 3.1, which was later upgraded to .NET 6, RDS MySQL,
 and SNS.
- Scrum and Agile methodologies were used with two-week sprints. Participated in daily standups
 to report progress and any possible impediments. Took part in weekly pre-grooming and
 grooming sessions to ensure stories were ready for the upcoming sprint. Engaged in sprint
 retrospectives to assess the previous sprint and what could be improved in the following sprint(s).
- Worked with DevOps to ensure efficient, quality releases and to build out microservices that were highly available, scalable, and cost efficient.
- Reviewed pull requests in GitLab to ensure code followed best practices, coding standards, and met security compliance.
- Worked closely with QA to ensure proper automated test coverage of microservices and wrote automated tests as needed resulting in significantly lower defects and increased reliability.

Software Developer, 2014 – 2019

Responsible for developing new features and maintaining existing features in legacy systems. Followed the software development lifecycle to ensure projects were completed on time and to company specifications.

- Helped rewrite the sign-in application of company's customer portal. This gave the customer a
 more modern interface to use that was much more secure than the previous sign-in process. PHP,
 MySQL, and SVN were used.
- Scrum and Agile methodologies were used with two-week sprints. Participated in daily standups
 to report progress and any possible impediments. Took part in weekly pre-grooming and
 grooming sessions to ensure stories were ready for the upcoming sprint. Engaged in sprint
 retrospectives to assess the previous sprint and what could be improved in the following sprint(s).
- Helped develop new features and fix customer-facing issues on company's customer portal and internal customer configuration application which reduced customer-facing issues and increased customer satisfaction.
- Worked on a new client application using microservices that delivered information to the client significantly faster than the existing application. These microservices were written in .NET Core 3.1 / .NET 6 using RDS MySQL, MongoDB, S3, SNS, SQS.

Systems Support Engineer, 2012 – 2014

Responsible for the monitoring of all production systems, as well as web applications and database servers.

- Created DML to remedy any data issues encountered from monitoring alerts, decreasing internal and external customer-facing issues and increasing internal and external customer satisfaction.
- Applied DML created by other developers to remedy applicable data issues.
- Reviewed web server logs for errors and determined the source of the errors. Delivered reports to the various development teams with a log of issues found for prioritization to be fixed.
- Created custom reports for customers utilizing PHP and setup to run using third-party scheduling software. This gave customers more flexibility both in report delivery and format delivery.
- Optimized code deployment scripts using Python and SVN making the deployment process faster and more reliable.

QA Engineer, 2011 - 2012

Responsible for performing system and acceptance testing of the various B2B and B2C web portals.

- Performed system and acceptance testing of a bug-free release, following Waterfall methodology, that allowed customers to utilize multiple bank accounts to handle the receipt of the end user's payments through various web portals.
- Performed system and acceptance testing of a release, following Waterfall methodology, that allowed the end users of B2B web portal to link multiple accounts with individual bill receipt/payment options.
- Performed system testing of various bug fixes to automated document factory and various web portals to increase performance, stability, and usability.

EDUCATION

Rutgers University – New Brunswick, NJ Full Stack Bootcamp – Graduate 8/2024

Middlesex County College – Edison, NJ Computer Science – 30 Credits